Trapped behind enemy lines. All they have is their hope.
Saints and Soldiers is a war, drama, action film directed by Ryan Little.
Five American soldiers fighting in Europe during World War II struggle to
return to Allied territory after being separated from U.S.
forces during the historic Malmedy Massacre.
Corporal Nathan 'Deacon' Greer, played by Corbin Allred.
Medic Steven Gould, played by Alexander Polinsky.
Flight Sergeant Oberon Winley, played by Kirby Heyborne.
Private Shirley 'Shirl' Kendrick, played by Larry Bagby.
Staff Sergeant Gordon Gunderson, played by Peter Holden.
Rudolph 'Rudi' Gertz, played by Ethan Vincent.
Saints and Soldiers is a 2003 war drama film directed by Ryan
Little and produced by Little and Adam Abel.
It is loosely based on events that took place after the
Malmedy massacre during the Battle of the Bulge.
The film stars Corbin Allred, Alexander Niver, Lawrence Bagby, and Peter Asle Holden as four American
soldiers trying to return a British airman with vital intelligence to the Allied lines.
After researching World War II and the Battle of the Bulge,
Little began shooting in January 2003 in Utah.
Filming lasted 30 days.
Little and Abel were able to save money on production by recruiting a group of World
War II reenactors who volunteered their services, costumes, and props.
Excel Entertainment released the film at festivals to garner
publicity before it was released to the public.
The movie won numerous Best Picture awards from over 15 film festivals.
Critical reception was generally positive with praise towards the message, story, performances
(particularly of Allred and Niver), production values, and action sequences.
Though the screenplay, pacing, and ties to Mormonism were criticized by some reviewers, several film scholars
argued that despite the Latter Day Saint (LDS)-related themes, the film appeals to a wide audience.
The movie's success launched its titular film series,
including three standalone sequels.
The film explores themes of nazi, winter, bravery, world war ii, belgium.
The tone is emotional.